Guide to the Phil Zwickler papers, circa 1979-1993
Zwickler, Phil papers, circa 1979-1993
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Phil Zwickler papers, circa 1979-1993
7564
Phil Zwickler, 1954-1991
12.2 cubic feet; 160 videocassettes; 5 DVDs.
Documents, photographs, film, videocassettes.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Documents, videos, and film from Phil Zwickler's work on "Rights and Reactions," as well as several other projects, including some material regarding "Fear of Disclosure," and miscellaneous files and photographs, mostly from 1987 to 1992.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Filmmaker and writer about gay and lesbian issues and the AIDS crisis, born June 1, 1954 and died from the complications of AIDS on May 7, 1991. With Jane Lippman, he produced and directed "Rights and Reactions: Lesbian and Gay Rights on Trial," an award-winning documentary covering the 1986 New York City Council hearings on the gay rights bill. Zwickler collaborated with David Wojnarowicz to produce "Fear of Disclosure," a short film about the issues gay men face dating in the context of AIDS. Zwickler also worked with experimental German film maker, Rosa von Praunheim, to produce "Silence Equals Death" and "Positive," both exploring the emotions and anger of people with AIDS. The film "Positive" includes interviews with Zwickler and two other men who were HIV-positive. He produced his final project, "The Needle Nightmares" (1991), with the help of David Meieran. Zwickler also worked as a news reporter, publishing stories in the Village Voice and serving as editor of the People with AIDS Coalition Newsline for a number of years. Before working in film and journalism, he taught literature in New York City public schools and community colleges.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Documents, publicity, funding proposals, correspondence, production notes, and video outtakes from Phil Zwickler's work on "Rights and Reactions," as well as several other documentary and video projects, including "Fear of Disclosure," "Silence = Death," and "Positive." Also, documentation of his work as editor for "PWA Coalition Newsline," and miscellaneous files and photographs, mostly from 1987 to 1992.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Zwickler, Phil, 1954-1991
Titles:
Rights and reactions.; Fear of disclosure.; Silence equals death.; Positive.; PWA Coalition newsline.
Subjects:
Gay men.; AIDS (Disease).; Gay liberation movement.; Gays--Laws and legislation.; Lesbians--Laws and legislation.; Dating (Social customs).
Form and Genre Terms:
Videotapes.; Documentaries.; Videocassettes.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
Available Copies:
Use copies are available for selected films and videos.
Note: Tapes designated as 3/4"* are 3/4" wide but shorter than regular 3/4" tapes. They can still be viewed using the 3/4" U Matic machine.
SERIES LIST
Series I. Manuscripts
Boxes 1, 18-19
A. Personal Files, 1987-1989
B. Realis Pictures, Inc.
C. "Rights and Reactions" 1987-1989
D. Other
Series II. Videos
Boxes 2-17, 20
A. Rights and Reactions
1. Masters
2. Production Dubs
3. Window Dubs
a. Series, Master Tapes
b. Series, Submasters
B. Fear of Disclosure
C. Koch and Phil
D. Act Up Demonstration
E. Sloan Kettering
F. Others
1. Master Edit
2. Demo Tapes
3. Others
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Manuscripts
  - Personal Files, 1987-1989
    - Resume, Personal narrative, and proposals for "Fear of disclosure", Undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Memorial service items and obituaries - collected by archivist Photographs, contact sheets, negatives, Undated (Box 1, Folder 42)
    - "[Canada?]/LA PZ 8/89," including photos of mountains, urban centers, Zwickler with a chiropractor, an ACT UP meeting, national lesbian and gay rights activist Urvashi Vaid, etc., August 1989 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - "Lawkerstein [?], [Mayor] Koch, Joseph", April 4, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - "Edison #1001," an ACT UP rally in New York City including photographs of arrests and of artist Keith Haring, Undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Letter to Allen, Caren and Parents; also pictures and a drawing, December 31, 1989 (Box 18, Folder 41)
  - Realis Pictures, Inc.
    - Agreements with Zwickler about "Rights and Reactions," also records about Realis; involvement with Zwickler's memorial service, 1987-1991 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Cornell correspondence, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - "Rights and Reactions" 1987-1989
    - Memos of agreement, correspondence, etc. with Realis (Box 1, Folder 7-8)
    - Jane Lippman agreement (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Financial records: General (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Financial records: Petty cash logs (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Financial records: Bank statements (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Financial records: Final financial form (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Financial records: Contributions and grants9 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Financial records: New York State Council on the Arts (Box 1, Folder 15-18)
    - Publicity and correspondence (Box 1, Folder 19-23)
    - Gay film festivals (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Requests for information about renting (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Research files (Box 1, Folder 26-27)
    - Release forms (Box 1, Folder 28-29)
    - Photograph (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Credits (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Press release (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - Tapestry Productions correspondence (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - Editing sheets (Box 1, Folder 41)
    - Rights and Reactions sticker and invitation (Box 18, Folder 10)
    - Funding Proposal (Box 18, Folder 11)
    - Technicals, content, production and post-production, miscellaneous (Box 18, Folder 12)
    - Post-production, editing, assemblies, selects, 2 notebooks (Box 18, Folder 13)
    - Notes (Box 18, Folder 14)
    - Publicity (Box 18, Folder 15)
    - Festival International du Film Documentaire Nyon, 1987 (Box 18, Folder 16)
    - Berlin Film Festival, 1987-1988 (Box 18, Folder 17)
    - Filmfest DC, 1988 (Box 18, Folder 18)
    - NY Lesbian and Gay Experimental Film Festival, 1988 (Box 18, Folder 19)
    - Reviews, 1987-1988 (Box 18, Folder 20)
    - Correspondence and Awards, 1987-1989 (Box 18, Folder 21)
    - Correspondence, clippings and publicity in folder labeled "To Dad" (Box 18, Folder 22)
    - Letter, Owen Levy to [Allen or Seymour] Zwickler, July 7, 1992 (Box 18, Folder 23)
    - Script outline and notes (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Other
    - "Fear of Disclosure": Notes on script and production (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - "Fear of Disclosure": Shirley Kaufer interview (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - "Fear of Disclosure": "(In)visible Women" and other work of the Fear of Disclosure project, 1991-1992 (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - "Images and Realities: Towards New Cultural Initiatives in the Lesbian and Gay Community," plans for a retreat (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - Proposal notes (Box 1, Folder 38)
    - Subject file on AIDS (Box 1, Folder 39-40)
    - Photograph of Phil Zwickler (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - Peter Kunz-Opfersei Memorial, 1989 (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - Los Angeles Trip, July 1989 (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - PWA Coalition Newsline, Phil Zwickler editor, January 1990 (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - Re: Outright newspaper, administrative information, circa 1988 (Box 18, Folder 5)
    - Phil Zwickler Broadsides, publicity, 1990 (Box 18, Folder 6)
    - AIDS Articles, 1985 (Box 18, Folder 7)
    - Resume, Newspaper Stories by/about PZ, 1987-1989 (Box 18, Folder 8)
    - Resume, Newspaper Stories by/about PZ, 1987-1989 (Box 18, Folder 9)
    - Joseph Dunne, September 1989 (Box 18, Folder 34)
    - NY Gay and Lesbian Film Festival Catalog, 1993 (Box 18, Folder 35)
    - Info on AIDS in NYC that PZ had inserted in the Program for GMHC's Ringling Bros. Fundraising Program, 1983 (Box 18, Folder 36)
    - Miscellaneous AIDS and Lesbian/Gay Brochures, circa 1990 (Box 18, Folder 37)
    - GMHC administrative structure (Box 18, Folder 38)
    - Part of a publication by P.P.O.W., art, poetry, photographs (Box 18, Folder 39)
    - L.A. Festival Program, 1990 (Box 19+, Folder 1)
    - Cover for a record (LP) by Somerville/Steinbacheck/Bronski (Box 19+, Folder 2)
    - Clippings on AIDS treatments, research and government response, 1986-1991 (Box 19+, Folder 3)
  - "Fear of Disclosure" and David Wojnarowicz, 1989-1990
    - "Fear of Disclosure" letters of support, etc., 1989-1990 (Box 18, Folder 24)
    - "Fear" at NY International Festival of Lesbian and Gay Film, 1990 (Box 18, Folder 25)
    - "Fear" at Berlin International Film Festival, 1990 (Box 18, Folder 26)
    - "Fear" at San Francisco Lesbian and Gay Film Festival and at Los Angeles Gay and Lesbian Film and Video Festival, 1990 (Box 18, Folder 27)
    - David Wojnarowicz Biography (Box 18, Folder 28)
    - Wojnarowicz: "Target City Hall: An AIDS Guide to NYC in 1989" (Box 18, Folder 29)
  - "Positive" & "Silence = Death" and Rosa von Praunheim
    - Phil's Positive Diary and other materials re: Positive, 1990-1991 (Box 18, Folder 30)
    - "Silence = Death", "Positive", and "Fear and Disclosure": reviews and publicity, 1990 (Box 18, Folder 31)
    - "Silence = Death", "Positive": reviews, 1990 (Box 18, Folder 32)
    - Application to NYSCA for Distribution of Film: "Silence = Death" (Box 18, Folder 33)
- Series II. Videos
  - A. Rights and Reactions
    - Virginia Apuzzo Clip, 1
      - Original Copy, 3/4" (Box 2)
    - Humm: Tape 3.3-11-86 (R and R Cam Orig. Submaster made later), 2
      - Original Copy, 3/4"* (Box 3)
    - Full interviews from Rights and Reactions, 163
      - Original Copy, DVD (Box 14)
    - Masters
      - Submaster #1: 2, 3, 6 on one tape (236 master 2, 3, 6), 3
        - Original, 3/4" (Box 2)
      - Tape #4 3-11-86: Reactions Sal Albanese, Salvation Army: Reaction, Upstairs Wine Shots, Decor: interview; Reel 4 TC 4, 4
        - Original, 3/4"* (Box 3)
      - Talking to Bricker, Banks, Ginny Appuzo: Committee Curatway N.G., Moynihan: Black Minister, Bob Grant + Dreyfoos; Dear; Reel 8 T.C. 8, 5
        - Original, 3/4"* (Box 3)
      - Reel: 12, 13; TC: 12, 13 (Submaster 12, 13), 6
        - Original, 3/4" (Box 2)
      - Tape 16, 3-18-86: Morning Demo Anti-Intro 2; Reel 16 TC 16, 7
        - Original, 3/4"* (Box 3)
      - Tape 17, 3-18-86: McCay interview Morning Demo; Reel 17 TC 17, 8
        - Original, 3/4"* (Box 3)
      - 3-20-86: City Hall Article, Anti-Gay Primo; Reel 27 TC 2:00:00, 9
        - Original, 3/4"* (Box 3)
      - N. Y. Post Demonstration G. L. A. D. 12/1/85; Tape 2, Reel 32 TC 7:00, 10
        - Original, 3/4"* (Box 3)
      - Master 33: New York Post Deminstration [sic] 12/1/85; #8, Reel 33 TC 8:00, 11
        - Original, 3/4"* (Box 3)
      - AIDS Memorial Service 12 23 85, #9, Camera 1; G. O'Connor: Camera Director; Reel 34 TC 9:00, 12
        - Original, 3/4"* (Box 3)
      - AIDS Memorial Service, #10, Camera 2; Reel 35 TC 10:00, 13
        - Original, 3/4"* (Box 3)
      - AIDS Memorial Service 12-23-85, Camera 3, Tape 36 Cam Orig; Reel 36 TC13:30, 14
        - Original, 3/4"*
      - Film Festival Rally/Demonstration 1-9-86, Tape 37 Cam. Orig. T.C. Ch. 2; Reel 37 TC 14:30, 15
        - Original, 3/4"* (Box 3)
    - Production Dubs
      - G. O. camera: Tape 1 Opening, Ed Koch: Reactions (lt), 2 Dear Brother Powick; Weiss, PAPP, 3 Reactions Harvey Irving getting thrown out, Reaction; Protection Dub reels: 1, 2, 3, 16
        - Original, 3/4" (Box 2)
      - Dub VIII: 16.17 3-18-86 Morning Anti Gay Men, AFT Demo; Protection Dub reels: 16, 17, 20, 17
        - Original, 3/4" (Box 2)
      - Dub IX: 21 AFT Demo: 18, 19, Silva; Protection Dub reels: 18, 19, 18
        - Original, 3/4" (Box 2)
      - Dub XI: 3-20-86 1. Alter pt. II, 2. Pro gay stories, 3. Anti gay (?); Protection Dub reels: 25, 26, 27, 19
        - Original, 3/4" (Box 2)
      - Dub XII: 28 Miriam, David, Joyce; 29 Vote + Hallway; 30 Dear, Party; Protection Dub reels 28, 29, 30, 20
        - Original, 3/4" (Box 2)
    - Window Dub
      - Window Dub #3: Tapes #4 + 5, 21
        - Original, 3/4" (Box 2)
      - Window Dub #4: Tapes #7, 8, and 9 with Burn-in, 22
        - Original, 3/4" (Box 4)
      - Window Dub #5: Tape #9 (contd) with Burn-in, 23
        - Original, 3/4"* (Box 3)
      - Window Dub #7: Tape #14 Contd., Burn-in, 24
        - Original, 3/4" (Box 4)
      - Window Dub #9: Tapes #15, 16, and 17 with Burn-in, 25
        - Original, 3/4" (Box 4)
      - Window Dub #12: Tapes #21, 22, and 23 with Burn-in, 26
        - Original, 3/4" (Box 4)
      - Window Dub #15: Tapes #29, 30, 31; Tapes 4, 5, and 6 with Burn-in, 27
        - Original, 3/4" (Box 4)
      - Window Dub #34: Tapes #18A, 19A; Gay Rights Reel 18 + 19 (partial) w/vis. T.C., 28
        - Original, 3/4" (Box 4)
      - Window Dub #35: Tape 19A Contd.; Gay Rights, Reel 19a (complete) w/vis. T.C.; Joyce Hunter, 29
        - Original, 3/4" (Box 4)
    - A Series, Master Tapes
      - Master Tape 1A Jan 9, 1987: Jim Levin, Human Rights Commissioner; T.C. - Ch. 2 Master 1a/101, 30
        - Original, 3/4"* (Box 3)
      - Master Tape 2A 1-9-87: Jim Levin HRC Commissioner; T.C. - Ch. 2 Master 2a/102, 31
        - Original, 3/4"* (Box 3)
      - Master Tape 3A 1-9-87: Jim Levin HRC Commissioner; T.C. - Ch. 2 Master 3a/103, 32
        - Original, 3/4"* (Box 3)
      - Master Tape 4A 1-9-87: Jim Levin HRC Commissioner; T.C. - Ch. 2 Master 4a/104, 33
        - Original, 3/4"* (Box 3)
      - Master Tape 5A 1-9-87: Jim Levin HRC Commissioner; T.C. - Ch. 2 Master 5a/105, 34
        - Original, 3/4"* (Box 3)
      - Master Tape 6A 1-9-87: Tape 6; interview of Stoddard; 6a Master 106; T.C. - Ch 2 Master 6a/106, 35
        - Original, 3/4"* (Box 5)
      - Andy Humm Interview 2-28-87: Camera Original 8a; T.C. - Ch. 2 Master 8A/108, 36
        - Original, 3/4"* (Box 5)
      - Andy Humm Interview 2-28-87: Camera Original 9A; T.C. - Ch. 2 Master 9A/109, 37
        - Original, 3/4"* (Box 5)
      - Andy Humm Interview 2-28-87: Camera Original 10A; T.C. - Ch. 2 Master 10A/110, 38
        - Original, 3/4"* (Box 5)
      - Andy Humm Interview 2-28-87: Camera Original 11A; T.C. - Ch. 2 Master 11A/111, 39
        - Original, 3/4"* (Box 5)
      - Andy Humm Interview 2-28-87: Camera Original 12A; T.C. - Ch. 2 Master 12A/112; Audio: Ch 1 T.C.: Ch 2, 40
        - Original, 3/4"* (Box 5)
      - Master 13A, Camera Original: 8-11-86: AIDS Preacher, "Wages of Sin", 41
        - Original, 3/4"* (Box 5)
      - Master Graphix 14A, Camera Originals: Newspapers; Master 114/14A, 42
        - Original, 3/4" (Box 4)
      - Master 22a: Andy VO; (Sub) Master 22a/122, 43
        - Original, 3/4" (Box 4)
      - 15A Rights + Reactions, 44
        - Original, Beta cam (Box 12)
      - 16A/116 Rights + Reactions, 45
        - Original, Beta cam (Box 12)
      - 17A Rights + Reactions 117 Master, 46
        - Original, VHS (Box 12)
      - 118/18A Rights + Reactions, 47
        - Original, VHS (Box 12)
      - Shox Lumania: Stranger, Falling Down (Takes 1-3 of each), August 20, 1982, 48
        - Original, 1" (Box 5)
      - Still Photos - Bettye Lane, Graphix: Camera Orig. 7A: Historic stills b+w (7A Master) [ RESTRICTED], 49
        - Original, 3/4" (Box 6)
      - Window Dub #36, Tape 20a [ RESTRICTED], 50
        - Original, 3/4" (Box 6)
      - Window Dub #37, Tape 21a [ RESTRICTED], 51
        - Original, 3/4" (Box 6)
      - Window Dub #39, Tape 23a (Protection Dub) [ RESTRICTED], 52
        - Original, 3/4" (Box 6)
      - Master 23A: 4/20/87 [ RESTRICTED], 53
        - 1" (Box 9)
      - Master 24a: Joyce Kiss Still, Bill, HRC Bk. (24A Master) [ RESTRICTED], 54
        - Original, 3/4" (Box 6)
    - B Series, Submasters
      - WNYC Council HR.ings: Submaster I; 201 Master 1b, 55
        - Original, 3/4" (Box 6)
      - WNYC Council HR.ings: Submaster Cutaways + Some B-Roll; 202 Master 2b, 56
        - Original, 3/4"* (Box 6)
      - WNYC Council HR.ings: Submaster II; 203 Master 3b, 57
        - Original, 3/4" (Box 6)
      - WNYC Council HR.ings: Submaster Cutaways II; 204 Master 4b, 58
        - Original, 3/4"* (Box 6)
      - WNYC Council HR.ings: Submaster III; 205 Master 5b [ RESTRICTED], 59
        - Original, 3/4" (Box 6)
      - Abigail 1983 - NYC Council Submaster: 206 Master 6b [ RESTRICTED], 60
        - Original, 3/4"* (Box 6)
      - Fran Post-Bill Pass Celeb. Submaster: Master 7b [ RESTRICTED], 61
        - Original, 3/4"* (Box 6)
      - GCN 7-1-86 Submaster: Master 8b [ RESTRICTED], 62
        - Original, 3/4"* (Box 6)
  - B. Fear of Disclosure
    - Fear Tape #1: Train Track; "Xuxa" Master Copy Off-Line #1, 63
      - Original, 3/4" (Box 7)
    - Fear I: Both Guys + Paul Solo, 8-89 Dancers source materials (6 of 6), Aug. 1989; 64; RSM# 1076
      - Original, 3/4"* (Box 5)
      - Preservation Copy, SP Betacam (Box 15)
      - Use Copy, VHS (Box 16)
    - Fear II: Dance, Dancers source materials (5 of 6), Aug. 1989; RSM# 1075; 65
      - Original, 3/4"* (Box 5)
      - Preservation Copy, SP Betacam (Box 15)
      - Use Copy, VHS (Box 16)
    - Fear Part II: 11-89, 66
      - Original, 3/4"* (Box 5)
    - Fear IV: Text 1, Music, 8-89 (source materials) (3 of 6), Aug. 1989; 67
      - Original, 3/4" (Box 7)
      - Preservation Copy, SP Betacam (Box 15)
      - Use Copy, VHS (Box 16)
    - Fear V: Music, 8-89, 68
      - Original, 3/4" (Box 7)
    - Fear: 2X Visuals, 69
      - Original, 3/4"* (Box 5)
    - Fear: David Wojnarowicz Text Voice-Over (4 of 6), RSM# 1074; 70
      - Original, 3/4" (Box 7)
      - Preservation Copy, SP Betacam (Box 15)
      - Use Copy, VHS (Box 16)
    - Fear: Text II (2 of 6), RSM# 1072; 71
      - Original, 3/4" (Box 7)
      - Preservation Copy, SP Betacam (Box 15)
      - Use Copy, VHS (Box 16)
    - Fear: Music; Tease, Assembly 2, 72
      - Original, 3/4"* (Box 5)
    - Fear: Out takes; Wojnar, Zwickler, Petra Commercials, 73
      - Original, 3/4" (Box 7)
  - C. Koch and Phil
    - Koch + PZ: Koch #1 Jena (PZ Q. It wasn't until '83 that you met with people to deal with AIDS crises)(1 of 5), 1989; RSM# 1082A; 74
      - Original, 3/4"* (Box 5)
      - Preservation Copy, SP Betacam (Box 15)
      - Use Copy, VHS (Box 16)
    - Koch + PZ: Koch #2 Jena (PZ Q. Citizen Commission to Foster Coop. State and Government on AIDS) (2 of 5), 1989; RSM# 1082B; 75
      - Original, 3/4"* (Box 5)
      - Preservation Copy, SP Betacam (Box 15)
      - Use Copy, VHS (Box 16)
    - Koch + Phil: John #1 (PZ Q. Citizen Commission to Foster Coop. State and Government on AIDS) (3 of 5), 1989; RSM# 1082C; 76
      - Original, 3/4"* (Box 8)
      - Preservation Copy, SP Betacam (Box 15)
      - Use Copy, VHS (Box 16)
    - Koch + Phil: John C. #2 (PZ Q. Citizen Commission to Foster Coop. State and Government on AIDS) (4 of 5), 1989, RSM# 1082D; 77
      - Original, 3/4"* (Box 8)
      - Preservation Copy, SP Betacam (Box 15)
      - Use Copy, VHS (Box 16)
    - Koch + Phil: Cut-a-ways (5 of 5), 1989, RSM# 1082E; 78
      - Original, 3/4"* (Box 8)
      - Preservation Copy, SP Betacam (Box 15)
      - Use Copy, VHS (Box 16)
  - D. ACT UP Demonstration
    - ACT UP Demo. #1 (1 of 8), Mar. 28, 1989, RSM# 1083A; 79
      - Original, 3/4" (Box 8)
      - Preservation Copy, SP Betacam (Box 15)
      - Use Copy, VHS (Box 16)
    - ACT UP Demo. #2 (2 of 8), 3/28/89, RSM# 1083B; 80
      - Original, 3/4" (Box 8)
      - Preservation Copy, SP Betacam (Box 15)
      - Use Copy, VHS (Box 16)
    - ACT UP Demo. #3 (3 of 8), 3/28/89, RSM# 1083C; 81
      - Original, 3/4" (Box 8)
      - Preservation Copy, SP Betacam (Box 15)
      - Use Copy, VHS (Box 16)
    - ACT UP Demo. #4 (4 of 8), 3/28/89, RSM# 1083D; 82
      - Original, 3/4" (Box 8)
      - Preservation Copy, SP Betacam (Box 15)
      - Use Copy, VHS (Box 16)
    - ACT UP Demo. #5 (5 of 8), 3/28/89, RSM# 1083E; 83
      - Original, 3/4" (Box 8)
      - Preservation Copy, SP Betacam (Box 15)
      - Use Copy, VHS (Box 16)
    - ACT UP Demo. #7 (6 of 8), 3/28/89, RSM# 1083F; 84
      - Original, 3/4" (Box 8)
      - Preservation Copy, SP Betacam (Box 15)
      - Use Copy, VHS (Box 16)
    - ACT UP Demo. #8 (7 of 8), 3/28/89, RSM# 1083G; 85
      - Original, 3/4" (Box 8)
      - Preservation Copy, SP Betacam (Box 15)
      - Use Copy, VHS (Box 16)
    - ACT UP Demo. #9 (8 of 8), 3/28/89, RSM# 1083H; 86
      - Original, 3/4" (Box 8)
      - Preservation Copy, SP Betacam (Box 15)
      - Use Copy, VHS (Box 16)
    - ACT UP Demo, Final Edit, 3/28/89, RSM# 1084; 87
      - Preservation Copy, SP Betacam (Box 15)
      - Use Copy, VHS (Box 16)
  - E. Sloan Kettering
    - "Sloan Kettering Demo (2)" (1 of 3), 7/24/87, RSM# 1079A; 88
      - Original, 3/4" (Box 8)
      - Preservation Copy, SP Betacam (Box 20)
      - Use Copy, VHS (Box 17)
    - "Sloan Kettering Demo (3)" (2 of 3), 7/24/87, RSM# 1079B; 89
      - Original, 3/4" (Box 8)
      - Preservation Copy, SP Betacam (Box 20)
      - Use Copy, VHS (Box 17)
    - "Sloan Kettering Demo (3)" (3 of 3), 7/24/87, RSM# 1079C; 90
      - Original, 3/4" (Box 7)
      - Preservation Copy, SP Betacam (Box 20)
      - Use Copy, VHS (Box 17)
      - Use Copy, DVD (Box 17)
  - F. Others
    - Fran/Mstr. 3-20-86: Rally (tape 1) [ RESTRICTED], 91
      - Original, 3/4" (Box 8)
    - Fran/Mstr. 3-20-86: Rally, Master #2 [ RESTRICTED], 92
      - Original, 3/4" (Box 8)
    - Fran/Mstr. 3-20-86: Rally after passing of bill, Master 3 [ RESTRICTED], 93
      - Original, 3/4" (Box 8)
    - "Herstory," tape #24: Anti-Lesbian Violence Interview with Joyce Hunter, 10-31-82, #1 of 3 [ RESTRICTED], 94
      - Original, 3/4" (Box 8)
    - "Herstory," tape #25: Anti-Lesbian Violence Interview with Joyce Hunter, 10-31-82, #2 of 3 [ RESTRICTED], 95
      - Original, 3/4" (Box 9)
    - "Herstory," tape #26: Anti-Lesbian Violence Interview with Joyce Hunter, 10-31-82, #3 of 3 [ RESTRICTED], 96
      - Original, 3/4" (Box 9)
    - "Herstory," tape #33: #7 - City Council Hearing on Gay Rights Bill 2/22/83. Includes: Concluding speeches of Friedlander + Messinger. Roll call. Speech by Long. Audience chants "Justice!" w/banner singing, pink papers triangles on floor. [ RESTRICTED], 97
      - Original, 3/4" (Box 9)
    - "Herstory," tape #34: #8 City Council Hearing on Gay Rights Bill 2/22/83; Violence Against Lesbians tape: Outside City Hall: Police put arrested people into van. Banner inside van. Interview with Pat B. [ RESTRICTED], 98
      - Original, 3/4" (Box 9)
    - PZ in Los Angeles, 1989, Tape 1, 99; Sections of this tape were preserved on DVC tape, item #162; This section may also be found on-line at http://rmc.library.cornell.edu/HSC/zwickler/nav.htm
      - Original, 3/4" (Box 7)
    - PZ in Los Angeles, 1989, Tape 2, 100; Sections of this tape were preserved on DVC tape, item #162; This section may also be found on-line at http://rmc.library.cornell.edu/HSC/zwickler/nav.htm
      - Original, 3/4" (Box 7)
    - PZ in Los Angeles: Agent Orange AM + PM News, 101
      - Original, 3/4" (Box 10)
    - Protest re: Hardwick #1, Dub from 3/4", 102
      - Original, V-174; 3/4" (Box 9)
      - Use copy, V-169; VHS (Box 14)
    - Protest re: Hardwick #2, Dub from 3/4", 103
      - Original, V-175; 3/4" (Box 9)
      - Use copy, V-170; VHS (Box 14)
    - Tape #4: Gay Liberation Movement: Koch + Phil, (20 Years of GLM) 5/19/89, 104
      - Original, 3/4" (Box 9)
    - Phil Zwickler Interview and Speech, RSM# 1080; 105
      - Original, 3/4" (Box 9)
      - Preservation Copy, SP Betacam (Box 20)
      - Use Copy, VHS (Box 17)
    - Phil Zwickler: AIDS Tape #1 Blood Bank", 7/8/83, RSM# 1078; 106
      - Original, 3/4" (Box 9)
      - Preservation Copy, SP Betacam (Box 20)
      - Use Copy, VHS (Box 17)
    - Blue Mountain, Autumn 1989: Chris Shaw, Boat Launch, Intv John + Barbara (40 min.), 107
      - Original, 3/4" (Box 10)
    - "WNYC" Tape #1: Gay Rights Hearing, 3-11-86: WNYC/Stock Ftge [WNYC has rights!!] [ RESTRICTED], 108
      - Original, 3/4" (Box 10)
    - "WNYC" Tape #2: Gay Rights Hearing, 3-11-86: WNYC/Stock Ftge [WNYC has rights!!] [ RESTRICTED], 109